<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-01-16T21:14:12-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Alex Guo</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">10 Amazing Things I Learned From Vsauce</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/01/31/Vsauce.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="10 Amazing Things I Learned From Vsauce" /><published>2019-01-31T10:20:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-01-31T10:20:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/01/31/Vsauce</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/01/31/Vsauce.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/MichaelStevens.jpg&quot; width=&quot;670&quot; height=&quot;377&quot; alt=&quot;Michael Stevens&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size=&quot;2&quot; color=&quot;black&quot;&gt;Credit: Michael Stevens&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vsauce is a YouTube channel with 14 million subscribers run by host Michael Stevens. On the channel, he explores various fields of study ranging from physics to economics, asking thought-provoking questions like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Xc4xYacTu-E&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&quot;Which Way Is Down?&quot;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JTvcpdfGUtQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&quot;What Is The Speed of Dark?&quot;&lt;/a&gt; Such questions lead to captivating discussions from which I've learned a plethora of interesting facts and lessons. Here are 10 things Vsauce has taught me that you can bring up the next time you're at a party.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h1&gt; 1. The Egyptian Pyramids and the Ancient Romans &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Pyramids.png&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;388&quot; alt=&quot;Great Pyramids&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size=&quot;2&quot; color=&quot;black&quot;&gt;Credit: Vsauce&lt;/font&gt;
  
&lt;p&gt;&lt;font size=&quot;5&quot; color=&quot;grey&quot;&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yNLdblFQqsw&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Our Narrow Slice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Egyptian Pyramids were as old to the Ancient Romans as the Ancient Romans are to us. The Pyramids were constructed at around 2550BC while the Roman Empire lasted from about 753BC to 476AD. Considering the fact that humans have been around for about 200,000 years, it truly allows you to appreciate how far we've come as a species in recent years in terms of technology and culture.

&lt;h1&gt; 2. Wisdom of the Crowds &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/JellyBean.jpg&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;393&quot; alt=&quot;Jar of Jelly Beans&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size=&quot;2&quot; color=&quot;black&quot;&gt;Credit: Powderly Vuchnich&lt;/font&gt;
  
&lt;p&gt;&lt;font size=&quot;5&quot; color=&quot;grey&quot;&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dvKeCcxD3rQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;How Many Photos Have Been Taken?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Wisdom of the Crowds is a phenomenon where averaging a set of data taken from many different individuals yields a more accurate result than a single individual working alone. One example of this is when the BBC conducted an experiment where 160 people guessed the number of jelly beans in a jar. When these guesses were averaged, the result was merely five jelly beans off from the actual number. I also noticed this phenomenon in my chemistry class when we had to calculate the equilibrium constant for a chemical reaction. After averaging the values from each person in our class, the result was very close to the theoretical value. It's humbling to know that the errors of other people in a group can help balance and correct our own shortcomings.

&lt;h1&gt; 3. What future humans will miss &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/SolarEclipse.jpg&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;447&quot; alt=&quot;Total Solar Eclipse&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size=&quot;2&quot; color=&quot;black&quot;&gt;Credit: Jay Pasachoff, Sara Dwyer , Rachel Wagner-Kaiser, and Wendy Carlos&lt;/font&gt;
  
&lt;p&gt;&lt;font size=&quot;5&quot; color=&quot;grey&quot;&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7uiv6tKtoKg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;What Will We Miss?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Although, as Michael points in the video, modern humans will miss out on things like technological advancements or supernovas (unless we can somehow extend our lifespan for thousands of years), future humans won't be able to experience some of the things we take for granted. For instance, the Moon is moving away from Earth at about 1cm every year, meaning that in about 63 million years, total solar eclipses will no longer be possible. In the year 52,000, Niagra Falls will no longer exist because the water will have erroded the top of the falls all the way to Lake Erie. So although it may be disappointing that we're limited by our short lifespans, we should cherish what we have.

&lt;h1&gt; 4. The mere-exposure effect &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Lincoln.png&quot; width=&quot;713&quot; height=&quot;436&quot; alt=&quot;Abraham Lincoln Mirrored&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size=&quot;2&quot; color=&quot;black&quot;&gt;Credit: Radiolab&lt;/font&gt;
  
&lt;p&gt;&lt;font size=&quot;5&quot; color=&quot;grey&quot;&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zRP82omMX0g&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;INSIDE a Spherical Mirror&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Have you ever wondered why you don't like the way you look in photos? This could be caused by the mere-exposure effect, which is when we develop a preference for the things we are familiar with. When we see ourselves, we often look at our reflection in the mirror. However, a mirror laterally inverts the image it reflects, meaning that what you see in the mirror is different from what cameras and other people see. To see the effect this can have, look at the two images above. The one on the left shows Abraham Lincoln as seen from a camera, but the one of the right shows the mirrored image that Lincoln himself was used to seeing.

&lt;h1&gt; 5. Computer screens don't show true colour &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/RBG.png&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;395&quot; alt=&quot;Screens Magnified&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size=&quot;2&quot; color=&quot;black&quot;&gt;Credit: Vitensenteret i Trondheim&lt;/font&gt;
  
&lt;p&gt;&lt;font size=&quot;5&quot; color=&quot;grey&quot;&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=R3unPcJDbCc&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;This Is Not Yellow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
When you see something yellow like a banana, you are seeing light with a wavelength of about 570nm. However, if you are looking at yellow on a computer screen, you are not seeing &quot;true&quot; yellow. This is because each pixel on a screen can only produce red, green, or blue light. Despite this, a screen can still fool you into seeing other colours. The human retina contains three types of cone cells which are each suited to detect a certain colour. One detects red, another detects green, and the third detects blue. The wavelength for yellow length is between the wavelengths for green and red light, so when you see &quot;true&quot; yellow both the green and red cones are activated which is interpreted as yellow. To simulate yellow light, a screen can show some green and red light since the pixels are too small to individually distinguish.

&lt;h1&gt; 6. Astronauts are not weightless &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Astronauts.jpg&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;463&quot; alt=&quot;Sandra Magnus&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size=&quot;2&quot; color=&quot;black&quot;&gt;Credit: Amusing Planet&lt;/font&gt;
  
&lt;p&gt;&lt;font size=&quot;5&quot; color=&quot;grey&quot;&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jTL_sJycQAA&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;What if You Were Born in Space?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
It's a common misconception that astronauts aboard space shuttles or the ISS experience zero gravity, allowing them to float around. Astronauts on the ISS actually experience about 90% of the gravity people on Earth do. The reason they are able to float is because they are in a state of freefall. The ISS orbits the Earth at around 28,000km/h, which is fast enough that the ISS falls to Earth at the same rate that the Earth curves away from it, creating a feeling of weightlessness. 

&lt;h1&gt; 7. Zipf's law &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/MobyDick.gif&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;572&quot; alt=&quot;Word frequency and rank in Moby Dick&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size=&quot;2&quot; color=&quot;black&quot;&gt;Credit: Wikimedia Commons&lt;/font&gt;
  
&lt;p&gt;&lt;font size=&quot;5&quot; color=&quot;grey&quot;&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fCn8zs912OE&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Zipf Mystery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Zipf's law is a phenomenon in language where the number of times a word occurs in a text can be approximated with its frequency rank. This means that the second most common word will occur about half as many times as the most common word, the third most common word will occur about a third as many times as the most common word, and so on. Plotting a graph with of the log of the frequency against the log of the rank will yield a linear plot as shown above. This has been observed in all languages, but is not limited to linguistics. As Michael mentions, Zipf's law is present in city populations, the amount of traffic websites receive, earthquake magnitudes, and more. The crazy thing is that we have no idea why this occurs.

&lt;h1&gt; 8. Blindsight &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Blindsight.jpg&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;405&quot; alt=&quot;Person with blindsight&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size=&quot;2&quot; color=&quot;black&quot;&gt;Credit: The Atlantic&lt;/font&gt;
  
&lt;p&gt;&lt;font size=&quot;5&quot; color=&quot;grey&quot;&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CSf8i8bHIns&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;What is Déjà vu?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The human brain contains a visual cortex which receives information from the retinas, allowing us to see. Information from the retina is also sent to the amygdala, which processes emotions, and the tectum, which is involved with preliminary visual processing. This means that people who have become blind because of damage to the visual cortex are still able to unconsciously process visual information. Despite being completely blind, these individuals are able to avoid obstacles on the ground and can feel emotion when presented with images of different human facial expressions. This is known as blindsight and it reveals a lot about the subconscious part of the human brain.

&lt;h1&gt; 9. It's impossible to literally touch something &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Touch.png&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;393&quot; alt=&quot;Representation of sitting down&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size=&quot;2&quot; color=&quot;black&quot;&gt;Credit: Vsauce&lt;/font&gt;
  
&lt;p&gt;&lt;font size=&quot;5&quot; color=&quot;grey&quot;&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yE8rkG9Dw4s&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;You Can't Touch Anything&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
When we think of two objects as touching, we would think that there would be no space between them. At an atomic level however, there will always be a gap because electrons in atoms repel each other. This means that when you sit down, you are technically hovering over the chair. In order to be as close as possible to touching, atoms must chemically react with each other by sharing electrons. Knowing this, we can say with certainty that the people who you have been the closest to touching are your parents and children. This is because your mother and father's DNA reacts in the womb to create you. And that's touching (pun intended).

&lt;h1&gt; 10. Regrets are like carvings on a tree &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/TreeCarving.jpg&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; alt=&quot;Tree Carving&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size=&quot;2&quot; color=&quot;black&quot;&gt;Credit: EyeEm&lt;/font&gt;
  
&lt;p&gt;&lt;font size=&quot;5&quot; color=&quot;grey&quot;&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dvKeCcxD3rQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;m͏̺͓̲̥̪í͇͔̠ś̷͎̹̲̻̻̘̝t̞̖͍͚̤k̥̞à̸͕̮͍͉̹̰͚̰ẹ̶̢̪s͏̨͈̙̹̜͚̲ ̛͟&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I absolutely love this metaphor from Ze Frank that Michael shares when talking about our past. Think of regrets and bad memories as carvings on a tree. The carvings won't go away or fade and they'll remain in their original spot forever. Pretty depressing right? Well, the tree itself doesn't have to be held down by these carvings. It can continue growing, becoming taller and gaining new branches. The regret may not get smaller, but you can make it a smaller part of yourself. So whenever you're lamenting over a failed test or a breakup, just remember that, like a tree, you can grow to make that experience something insignificantly small.

&lt;p&gt;I hope these facts were as interesting and mind-blowing to you as they were to me. If you want to learn more, I highly recommend that you check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC6nSFpj9HTCZ5t-N3Rm3-HA&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Vsauce&lt;/a&gt; on YouTube.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
 

&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Credit: Michael Stevens Vsauce is a YouTube channel with 14 million subscribers run by host Michael Stevens. On the channel, he explores various fields of study ranging from physics to economics, asking thought-provoking questions like &quot;Which Way Is Down?&quot; and &quot;What Is The Speed of Dark?&quot; Such questions lead to captivating discussions from which I've learned a plethora of interesting facts and lessons. Here are 10 things Vsauce has taught me that you can bring up the next time you're at a party. 1. The Egyptian Pyramids and the Ancient Romans Credit: Vsauce Source: Our Narrow Slice The Egyptian Pyramids were as old to the Ancient Romans as the Ancient Romans are to us. The Pyramids were constructed at around 2550BC while the Roman Empire lasted from about 753BC to 476AD. Considering the fact that humans have been around for about 200,000 years, it truly allows you to appreciate how far we've come as a species in recent years in terms of technology and culture.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/12/25/hello.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome!" /><published>2018-12-25T10:20:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-12-25T10:20:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/12/25/hello</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/12/25/hello.html">&lt;p&gt;Hi everyone! Thank you for visiting my personal blog, Alex’s Anecdotes! As you may know, my name is Alex and I’m a high school student pursing a computer engineering degree.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This blog will highlight my experiences in computer engineering, as well as some of my personal and professional development experiences.  I’m looking forward to sharing my incredible experiences and journey with you. Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Hi everyone! Thank you for visiting my personal blog, Alex’s Anecdotes! As you may know, my name is Alex and I’m a high school student pursing a computer engineering degree. This blog will highlight my experiences in computer engineering, as well as some of my personal and professional development experiences. I’m looking forward to sharing my incredible experiences and journey with you. Stay tuned!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How My High School Experience Made Me A Better Person</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/12/25/FirstPost.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How My High School Experience Made Me A Better Person" /><published>2018-12-25T10:20:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-12-25T10:20:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/12/25/FirstPost</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/12/25/FirstPost.html">&lt;p&gt;Have you ever looked back on your life and thought about that one key moment that completely changed you and shaped who you are as a person today? For me, that key moment was entering high school. I believe that the competitive and foreign environment really pushed me to my limits and brought out a level of determination, perseverance, and diligence that I never knew I had. Additionally, the friendships and experiences that I’ve acquired through high school are things I will cherish for years to come. I want to talk about my journey and I why I believe that facing adversity and stepping outside of your comfort zone are essential to building your character.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Growing up, I’ve always lived a relatively comfortable and stable life. I attended the same elementary school from junior kindergarten to eight grade. I only ever moved houses once when I was three years old. Whenever my parents suggested moving houses I strongly opposed it for fear of losing my friends. Ultimately, this stubbornness had a negative impact on me since I ended up getting used to my current lifestyle which made me more reluctant to try new things.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The academic environment was also a limiting factor for me. I barely had to put in any effort to achieve high marks, and I was the go-to guy for my classmates whenever they didn’t understand something. There was no competition for me and no incentive for me to work hard. This caused me to have the view that I was better than my peers and also made me less willing to take risks in class since I felt that I was the perfect student who everyone looked up to.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
All of this was turned upside down when high school rolled around. Instead of going to my local school where most of my friends were going I went to another school to take the IB program.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
High school was completely different from elementary school. Suddenly, I was thrust into an incredibly competitive environment where I was no longer the top student, but an average one at best. The worst part for me was that there was not a single familiar face around with whom I could talk. I felt lost, scared, and alone.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I soon realized that I needed to put in the effort to make new friends and do well in my classes. Initially, it was challenging for me to meet new people since I’m an introverted person and I had never been the “new kid” at school. Over time, I became more comfortable with talking to strangers and ended up making a few close friends. My coursework was also much more difficult and my peers were all academically gifted. Additionally, most of my peers possessed talents like public speaking and leadership which I lacked. This motivated me to work harder and I found that this was very humbling for me. While in some classes like Mathematics I did well, in other classes like English I struggled. This allowed me to self-reflect on my strengths and weaknesses and acknowledge that I wasn’t the best at everything.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I think that if I had gone to my local school with most of my friends instead, I would’ve stayed with the same group of friends instead of trying to form new relationships and develop my social skills. I also wouldn’t have been in such a competitive environment, meaning that I wouldn’t have worked as hard in school.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I guess that if you were to take away something from this story, it would be that facing hardships and stepping outside of your comfort zone will end up benefitting you in the long run. Whether you’re moving schools, or learning a new language, the only way you will ever grow and become a better person is if you challenge yourself to face difficult situations. As the emperor from &lt;i&gt;Mulan&lt;/i&gt; said, “The flower that blooms in adversity is the most rare and beautiful of all.”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Have you ever looked back on your life and thought about that one key moment that completely changed you and shaped who you are as a person today? For me, that key moment was entering high school. I believe that the competitive and foreign environment really pushed me to my limits and brought out a level of determination, perseverance, and diligence that I never knew I had. Additionally, the friendships and experiences that I’ve acquired through high school are things I will cherish for years to come. I want to talk about my journey and I why I believe that facing adversity and stepping outside of your comfort zone are essential to building your character. Growing up, I’ve always lived a relatively comfortable and stable life. I attended the same elementary school from junior kindergarten to eight grade. I only ever moved houses once when I was three years old. Whenever my parents suggested moving houses I strongly opposed it for fear of losing my friends. Ultimately, this stubbornness had a negative impact on me since I ended up getting used to my current lifestyle which made me more reluctant to try new things. The academic environment was also a limiting factor for me. I barely had to put in any effort to achieve high marks, and I was the go-to guy for my classmates whenever they didn’t understand something. There was no competition for me and no incentive for me to work hard. This caused me to have the view that I was better than my peers and also made me less willing to take risks in class since I felt that I was the perfect student who everyone looked up to. All of this was turned upside down when high school rolled around. Instead of going to my local school where most of my friends were going I went to another school to take the IB program. High school was completely different from elementary school. Suddenly, I was thrust into an incredibly competitive environment where I was no longer the top student, but an average one at best. The worst part for me was that there was not a single familiar face around with whom I could talk. I felt lost, scared, and alone. I soon realized that I needed to put in the effort to make new friends and do well in my classes. Initially, it was challenging for me to meet new people since I’m an introverted person and I had never been the “new kid” at school. Over time, I became more comfortable with talking to strangers and ended up making a few close friends. My coursework was also much more difficult and my peers were all academically gifted. Additionally, most of my peers possessed talents like public speaking and leadership which I lacked. This motivated me to work harder and I found that this was very humbling for me. While in some classes like Mathematics I did well, in other classes like English I struggled. This allowed me to self-reflect on my strengths and weaknesses and acknowledge that I wasn’t the best at everything. I think that if I had gone to my local school with most of my friends instead, I would’ve stayed with the same group of friends instead of trying to form new relationships and develop my social skills. I also wouldn’t have been in such a competitive environment, meaning that I wouldn’t have worked as hard in school. I guess that if you were to take away something from this story, it would be that facing hardships and stepping outside of your comfort zone will end up benefitting you in the long run. Whether you’re moving schools, or learning a new language, the only way you will ever grow and become a better person is if you challenge yourself to face difficult situations. As the emperor from Mulan said, “The flower that blooms in adversity is the most rare and beautiful of all.”</summary></entry></feed>