<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-12-09T17:27:13-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Alex Guo</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">First Post</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/03/23/hello.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First Post" /><published>2016-03-23T10:20:00-04:00</published><updated>2016-03-23T10:20:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2016/03/23/hello</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2016/03/23/hello.html">&lt;p&gt;When I started this website about a month ago, I wasn’t sure exactly what it would look like or what kind of content I wanted to include. Thankfully, my older brother who’s an experienced computer programmer pointed me in the right direction and helped me create my website. That being said, I decided that one thing I wanted to have was a blog. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I’m starting this blog because I feel like it would be a good way for me to put my thoughts out there and say everything that’s on my mind. I guess this is like my personal diary, except it’s not really a diary since I’m publicizing it. This won’t be a very research or news-oriented blog, nor will it be really formal or professional; I’ll simply be writing about whatever’s on my mind.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
With all of that out of the way, I thought it would be nice to introduce myself a bit more&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">When I started this website about a month ago, I wasn’t sure exactly what it would look like or what kind of content I wanted to include. Thankfully, my older brother who’s an experienced computer programmer pointed me in the right direction and helped me create my website. That being said, I decided that one thing I wanted to have was a blog. I’m starting this blog because I feel like it would be a good way for me to put my thoughts out there and say everything that’s on my mind. I guess this is like my personal diary, except it’s not really a diary since I’m publicizing it. This won’t be a very research or news-oriented blog, nor will it be really formal or professional; I’ll simply be writing about whatever’s on my mind. With all of that out of the way, I thought it would be nice to introduce myself a bit more</summary></entry></feed>